Justin Goncalves

IT System Administrator

: 857-407-9412

②: justingoncalves34@gmail.com

: Boston, MA

?: https://www.linkedin.com/in/justingoncalves/

🔗 : https://justingoncalves34.github.io/Cybersecurity Journey/

For a detailed overview of my background, cybersecurity projects, certifications, and skills, please visit my GitHub portfolio

Projects, Activities, and Virtual Internships

Commonwealth Bank Intro to Cybersecurity Program (August 2024)

- Served as a Cybersecurity Generalist on the Commonwealth Bank Fraud Detection and Response team.
- Analyzed and visualized data using *Splunk* to identify fraud patterns.
- Managed a phishing and malware incident using the Incident Response Lifecycle, and authored a detailed incident report.
- Conducted penetration testing and recommended remediation strategies.

PwC Switzerland Cybersecurity Job Simulation Program (August 2024)

- Worked as a Cybersecurity Analyst on PwC's Digital Intelligence Team.
- Conducted risk assessments and developed layered security strategies.
- Wrote reports on network segmentation and firewall configurations.
- Delivered presentations on risk management strategies and recommended network security improvements.

Datacom Cybersecurity Virtual Experience Program (August 2024)

- Investigated an APT34 attack using the MITRE ATT&CK Framework, and other OSINT tools, and created a cybersecurity investigation report.
- Developed a risk matrix, conducted a risk assessment, and provided tailored recommendations to improve overall security posture.

NIST CSF Incident Response Project

- Developed a response plan for a DDoS attack using the *NIST Cybersecurity Framework*.
- Conducted a full post-incident analysis and recommended improvements for preventing future attacks.

InfoSec Data Handling Security Assessment Project

- Analyzed data-handling procedures for confidentiality, integrity, and availability in compliance with *NIST SP 800-53* Guidelines.
- Recommended security controls, encryption protocols, and access authorization measures to improve secure data handling.

Work Experience

Operations Manager/IT System Administrator

Digit Web Solutions - Remote | (Dec 2023 - Present)

- Led a team of developers and engineers to deliver custom web solutions for clients, optimized workflows for operational efficiency, and ensured client satisfaction.
- Managed IT operations, including system administration, technical support, web hosting, network security, and incident response.

Freelance Web Developer

Remote | (April 2021 - Dec 2023)

- Developed secure, responsive websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and frameworks like React, with a focus on performance and cross-browser compatibility.
- Implemented security features, including HTTPS, SSL certificates, and secure payment gateways, while optimizing site performance and SEO.

Certifications

- CompTIA Security+, (Expected Oct. 2024)
- Google Cybersecurity Professional, (2024)
- Qualys Vulnerability Management Detection and Response (VMDR), (2024)
- Qualys Cybersecurity Asset Management (CSAM) (2024)
- Qualys Vulnerability Management Scanning (VMS) (2024)
- U.S. Department of Homeland Security National Incident Management System (NIMS)
- o IS-100.C, IS-200.C, IS-700.B, IS-800.D, IS-230.E, IS-860.C, IS-906, IS-915, IS-916, IS-1300, IS-2500

Skills

Frameworks

NIST CSF (SP 800-53, 800-61, 800-171) | OWASP CIS Controls | PCI DSS | HIPAA | GDPR | NIMS SOC 1/SOC 2 | ISO/IEC 27001 | MITRE ATT&CK

Tools/Technologies

Splunk | Qualys | Wireshark | Burp Suite | Metasploit TCPDump | Chronicle | Azure + Sentinel

Security Operations & Monitoring

SIEM Tools | Threat Hunting | Log Analysis Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (IDS, IPS)

Core Competencies

Incident Detection and Response | Cryptology Vulnerability Management | Risk Assessment | Network Security | Identity and Access Management

Programming/Scripting

Python | SQL | Bash/Shell Scripting | HTML 5 | CSS

Education

University of Massachusetts - Dartmouth, MA Finance Major | (2019-2020, (2022-2023)

Relevant Coursework: Business Statistics, Financial Modeling, Operations Management, Risk Management, Project Management

Boston Latin School - Boston, MA High School Diploma (2019)

#1 Ranked high school in Massachusetts at the time of my graduation.